# Danh Tran

### Software Engineer

As a software developer with 6 years of experience, I have worked in both Games & Apps Development. I'm easy to adapt to new tasks, and very patient with the legacy codebase. I'd like to dig into the architecture, optimize the code, spend time to debug, and always think about "How to make it faster?" or "Is this code easy to understand?". Ideally, I hope to develop my career in Android App Development. I believe that my contribution to your company will be valuable for the products.



danhtran.dev@outlook.com

Pho Chi Minh, Vietnam

github.com/danhtran-dev

+84374268537

in linkedin.com/in/danhtrandev

●● medium.com/@danhtran-dev

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Senior Software Engineer**

ShopBack Group

03/2022 - Present

The ShopBack Group is Asia-Pacific's leading shopping and rewards platform, serving over 30 million shoppers across ten markets.

#### Responsibilities

- PIC of product Earn More & Challenge on Android. I contribute to the ideation, technical design, implementation, and unit testing for Android.
- Work with Product Design, Product Operation, and the QA team to implement new features and support our users' satisfaction.
- Collaborate with other Tech Teams to contribute technical design discussions.

### Senior Software Engineer

#### Zalo Group

04/2018 - 03/2022

Zalo Group builds world-class tech products used and loved by millions. Products: Zalo, Zing TV, Zing MP3, Bao Moi, Laban Key, Adtima.

#### Responsibilities

- Collaborate with the Product Design team to define, design, and refine product features.
- In charge of features such as Sticker, Voice, Edit Photo, Video, Messages Database, and more ... to produce user's needs.
- Maintain the existing codebase and create sophisticated solutions to complex technical problems.
- Optimize performance and fix critical production bugs and deliver them on time.

#### Game Developer

#### **VNG Corp**

09/2017 - 04/2018

VNG develops, produces, and publishes games to the global market

#### Responsibilitie

- Maintain the existing codebase, fix technical problems, and optimize the performance of the legacy source code.
- Product: Fish shot.
- Development Tool: Cocos2dx, C++, Cocos Creator, Js.

# Game Developer

YOMI Studio

04/2017 - 09/2017

A Game Studio produce mini-games on mobile to the global market

#### Responsibilities

- Collaborate with the Product Design team to define, design, and refine product features.
- Maintain the existing codebase and fix technical problems.
- Product: Mini-Games Puzzle.
- Development Tool: Cocos2dx, C++, Unity3D, C#, Android Studio, XCode.

# **SKILLS**



## **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

#### Been Together (03/2019 - Present)

 An android application help user can keep track on their love story. This app has over 1.000.000 downloads and 8.000 reviews on Google Play Store

#### 1010 Puzzle (01/2016 - Present)

 A Puzzle Game like Tetris but easier to play, help user relax. This game is alive on Google Play Store and App Store also.

### KBC Trivia & Quiz Game (04/2019 - 01/2021)

 A Quiz game like "Who Wants to Be a Millionaire?" TV Show. This game was published in India Google Play Store and get 3 millions downloads.

## **EDUCATION**

#### Bachelor's Degree

University Information Of Technology

09/2012 - 06/2017

Certificates

- BIG-O BLUE: INTERMEDIATE ALGORITHMS
- AlgoExpert Certificate

### **LANGUAGES**

Vietnamese English
Native or Bilingual Proficiency Professional Working Proficiency

# **INTERESTS**

